{
  "quiz1": [
    {
      "question": "The _____________ tells everything in the computer how to Act.",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "brake system",
        "operating system",
        "power system",
        "CPU",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "operating system",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "The operating system manages and controls everything in the system"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "CPU stands for __________.",
      "answer": "central processing unit",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "CPU is short for central processing unit"
    },
    {
      "question": "Volatile memory-must be connected to a power source",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "eSATA",
        "SATA",
        "RAM",
        "ROM",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "RAM",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "RAM"
    },
    {
      "question": "A computing device is an electronic machine that uses binary data to automatically perform calculations.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "A computing device does use binary data to automatically perform calculations."
    },
    {
      "question": "the fastest and the most expensive computer among all types of computers.",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "megacomputer",
        "mainframe",
        "supercomputer",
        "all-in-one-computer",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "supercomputer",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "supercomputer are the fastest and the most expensive computer among all types of computers."
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "In binary a 1 represents _____.",
      "answer": "on",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "In binary a 1 represents on"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "In binary a 0 represents _____.",
      "answer": "off",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "In binary a 0 represents off"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is required for someone to have a conversation with someone else over the Internet (select 3)",
      "type": "checkboxes",
      "choices": [
        "firewall",
        "network connection",
        "webcam",
        "microphone",
        "modem"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "network connection",
        "webcam",
        "microphone"
      ],
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Three essentials during quarantine "
    },
    {
      "question": "malware that has embedded kelogger to capture all the keystrokes and steal logins is considered",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "spyware",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "spyware is malware that has embedded kelogger to capture all the keystrokes and steal logins is considered"
    },
    {
      "question": "Some devices can be both input and output devices.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Some devices can be both input and output devices."
    },
    {
      "question": "What components are used to store data (select two)",
      "type": "checkboxes",
      "choices": [
        "SSD",
        "RAM",
        "Motherboard",
        "CPU"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "SSD",
        "RAM"
      ],
      "correct": [
        0,
        1
      ],
      "explanation": "SSD and RAM store data "
    },
    {
      "question": "speakers are NOT a standard input device",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "keyboard, microphone, and scanners are examples of standard input devices"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which group are examples of Cloud Storage? ",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Gmail, Facebook, Dropbox",
        "Document File, Pictures File, Temporary File",
        "CD, Flash Drive, Floppy Disk",
        "Outlook Express, Microsoft Word, Windows 7",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Gmail, Facebook, Dropbox ",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Gmail, Facebook, Dropbox are examples of Cloud Storage."
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of malware infection demands payments in order to avoid being disabled?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "ransomware",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "ransomware attacks demand payment"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "A computer's language is called________ code.",
      "answer": "binary",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "A computer language is also referred to as a binary code"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which component of a computer controls the entire system and is often called the brain of the computer?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "CPU",
        "User",
        "Monitor",
        "Software",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "CPU",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "CPU is the component of a computer controls the entire system and is often called the brain of the computer"
    },
    {
      "question": "The main hardware components of a home computer are:",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Excel, Word, Internet Explorer",
        "Monitor, CPU, Keyboard",
        "Word, Speakers, Printer",
        "Monitor, Mouse, Internet",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Monitor, CPU, Keyboard ",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Monitor, CPU, Keyboard are main hardware components of a home computer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Rom can read but cant write?",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Rom is an acronym for Read-Only Memory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Microsoft word is considered a spreadsheet.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "false",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Microsoft word is not a spreadsheet"
    },
    {
      "question": "Computer programs and games are called ____?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Entertainmentware",
        "Flashware",
        "Hardware",
        "Software",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Software",
      "correct": 3,
      "explanation": "Computer programs and games are Softwares"
    }
  ],
  "quiz2": [
    {
      "question": "variables declared with in a class, outside any method, with the static keyword?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Local Variable",
        "Instance Variable",
        "Class Variable",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Class Variable",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "Class Variables are variables declared with in a class, outside any method, with the static keyword"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default value of byte datatype in Java?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "0",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Default value of byte datatype is 0."
    },
    {
      "question": " Variables used in a switch statement can be used with which datatypes?(select three)",
      "type": "checkboxes",
      "choices": [
        "string",
        "int",
        "char",
        "double",
        "float"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "string",
        "int",
        "char"
      ],
      "correct": [
        0,
        1,
        2
      ],
      "explanation": "Variables used in a switch statement can only be a string, enum, byte, short, int, or char"
    },
    {
      "question": "a class declared as private be accessed outside it's package?",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "false",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "No, it's not possible to accessed outside it's package."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is NOT an advantage of Java sockets?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Sockets are flexible and sufficient",
        "It cause low network traffic",
        "allows only to send packets of raw data between applications",
        "easily implemented for general communications"
      ],
      "answer": "allows only to send packets of raw data between applications",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "The disadvantage is that Socket based communications allows only to send packets of raw data between applications."
    },
    {
      "question": "Polymorphism is the ability of an object to take on many forms.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Polymorphism is the ability of an object to take on many forms."
    },
    {
      "question": "An interface is a collection of abstract methods.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "An interface is a collection of abstract methods. A class implements an interface, thereby inheriting the abstract methods of the interface."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Multiple Inheritance?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "one class inheriting from more super classes",
        "more classes inheriting from one super class",
        "more classes inheriting from more super classes",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "one class inheriting from more super classes",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Multiple Inheritance is when one class inheriting from more super classes"
    },
    {
      "question": " A constructor ____?(select three)",
      "type": "checkboxes",
      "choices": [
        "Must have the same name as the class it is declared within",
        "Is used to create objects",
        "May be declared private",
        "Cannot be declared public"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Must have the same name as the class it is declared within",
        "Is used to create objects",
        "May be declared private"
      ],
      "correct": [
        0,
        1,
        2
      ],
      "explanation": "A constructor is used is all those three ways"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "_____ is denoted by leading zero in java?",
      "answer": "octal numbers",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Octal Numbers are denoted by leading zero in java; ex. 04"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "_____ is denoted by leading 0x or 0X in java?",
      "answer": "hexadecimal numbers",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Hexadecimal Numbers are denoted by leading 0x or 0X in java; ex. 0XF"
    },
    {
      "question": "To prevent any method from overriding, we declare the method as?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "final",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "final prevents methods from overriding"
    },
    {
      "question": "Break statement can be used as labels in Java",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Yes; ex. break one;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Java allows Default Arguments",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "false",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Java does not allow Default Arguments."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method of the Component class is used to set the position and size of a component?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "setBounds()",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "setBounds() method is used"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT true?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "An interface can extend another interface.",
        "A class which is implementing an interface must implement all the methods of the interface.",
        " An interface can implement another interface.",
        "An interface is a solution for multiple inheritance in java",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": " An interface can implement another interface.",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": " An interface can not implement another interface."
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "In object-oriented programming, new classes can be defined by extending existing classes. This is an example of _____?",
      "answer": "inheritance",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Inheritance extends existing classes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Given a class named student, which of the following is a valid constructor declaration for the class?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        " Student (student s) { }",
        "Student student ( ) { }",
        "Private final student ( ) { }",
        "Void student ( ) { }",
        "Static void student(){ }"
      ],
      "answer": "Student (student s) { }",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": " This is a valid constructor declaration for the class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a member of the java.lang package?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "List",
        "Queue",
        "Math",
        "Stack",
        "Process"
      ],
      "answer": "Queue",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": " Queue is a member of the java.lang package"
    },
    {
      "question": "Given the code\n\nString s1 = ”hi” ;\nString s2 = ”hi” ;\nString s3 = new String ( s1);\n\nWhich of the following would be true?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "s1 == s2",
        "s1 = s2",
        "s3 == s1",
        "s3=s1",
        "s1!=s2"
      ],
      "answer": "s1 == s2",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "hi is equal to hi; hence true."
    }
  ]
}
